AKI GAO

(703) 901-0568 | xiaoyu.akihiro.gao.com | iknowht.ml | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a Full Stack JavaScript Engineer with a passion for technology and innovation, in particular the web and distributed software systems. I offer three years of professional experience in full stack web application development from conception to delivery of performant and maintainable solutions using functional programming paradigms in an Agile environment. My expertise range from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly UX/UIs to scalable and fault-tolerant event-driven microservice infrastructures. In particular, I specialize in web application development using the React and Node is ecosystems, as well as cloud-native and distributed architectures using Docker and Kubernetes.

Skills

Languages: Development and Testing Tools:

JavaScript, Shell (Bash)

Git, Yarn, Lerna, Webpack, Babel, Jest, ESlint

UX/UI and Front End Technologies:

Sketch, HTML, CSS, Emotion, PostCSS, React,

Node.js, Express, GraphQL, Apollo Server, Knex,

Storybook, Redux, Apollo Client PostgreSQL, Redis

DevOps Tools: Infrastructure Technologies:

Helm, Skaffold, CircleCI Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform

Work Experience

User1st - Solutions Integrator, Washington, D.C.

January 2020 - Present

• Develops custom accessibility features and remediates websites for compliance with WCAG 2.1 AA standard and Section 508 guidelines for clients.

Alluminate - Full Stack Developer, Washington, D.C.

November 2017 - February 2018

- Provided high-level technology expertise and development capabilities for in-house and consulting work ranging from UX/UI to smart contract development.
- Designed and maintained the company's homepage as well as landing pages for several products.
- Designed and audited smart contracts for ERC-721 compatibility and general correctness for CryptoPets, an Ethereum-based game platform for collecting and battling digital pets.

Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist, Herndon, VA

May 2017 - November 2017

- Developed proof of concept Blockchain applications based on Ethereum for various government organizations, including the U.S. Treasury and the FDA.
- Worked across the stack from UX/UI design to implementation of front end and back end logic in React and Express respectively, as well as deployment to various cloud providers including AWS and Azure in an Agile environment.
- Acted as defacto Product Owner and Scrum Master when necessary to translate requirements from the stakeholder, and convert requirements into tasks to be distributed among team members.
- Participation, expertise and leadership in projects led to conversion of one project from a proof of concept work into a full-fledged proposal for a contract bid.

Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

August 2016

• B.S. Computer Engineering & B.S. Electrical Engineering